<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Mario Simoni</title><link>https://mariosimoni.github.io/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Mario Simoni</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mariosimoni.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://mariosimoni.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mariosimoni.github.io/about/</guid><description>Introduction Mario Simoni is a PhD student at the Department of Electronics and Communications of Politecnico di Torino.
His main research activities focus on emerging quantum hardware for quantum computing and quantum communication, from primary physical principles to design and optimisation strategies. He is particularly interested in the analysis and modelling of promising technologies, such as solid-state qubits, that have the potential to enhance current quantum information processing infrastructures.
In his free time, Mario loves travelling, reading poetry, taking pictures, visiting art galleries and listening to classical music.</description></item><item><title>Scientific activities</title><link>https://mariosimoni.github.io/scientific-activities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mariosimoni.github.io/scientific-activities/</guid><description>Publications M. Avitabile, G. A. Cirillo, M. Simoni, G. Turvani and M. Graziano, &amp;ldquo;Development of a multi-technology, template-based quantum circuits compilation toolchain&amp;rdquo;, Quantum Information Processing, vol. 21, no. 379, 2022. C. Caputo, M. Simoni, G. A. Cirillo, G. Turvani and M. Zamboni, &amp;ldquo;A simulator of optical coherent-state evolution in quantum key distribution systems&amp;rdquo;, Optical and Quantum Electronics, vol. 54, no. 689, 2022. M. Simoni, G. A. Cirillo, G. Turvani, M. Graziano, and M.</description></item></channel></rss>